So many things are possible,
Hay tantas posibilidades
we have to be open.
tenemos que estar abiertos.
Guru Mahārāj says, “Cast your faith towards the Infinite, towards Kṛṣṇa”,
Guru Maharaj dice, "Lanza tu fe hacia el Infinito, hacia K???a”,
whatever little faith we have.
la poquita fe que tengamos.
[Salvadore Dali, Do You Believe in God?]
Salvador Dalí, ¿Crees en Dios?
I mentioned Dali, Salvadore Dali, the surrealist painter.
Menciono a Dalí, Savador Dalí, el pintor surrealista
When they said to him, “Dali, do you believe in God?”
cuando le preguntaron, "Dalí, ¿crees en Dios?"
and he said, “Yes, but I have no faith”,
y él respondió, "Sí, pero no tengo fe",
that was, I thought, oh, honest answer!
Esa fue lo que yo llamaría, ¡una respuesta honesta!
He’s saying “Yes!”
Él dice, "¡Sí!"
And I believe that everyone believes in God, actually.
Y creo que todos de hecho creen en Dios.
This was my own opinion:
Es mi opinión personal:
everyone does.
todos lo hacen.
But, as Avadhūt Mahārāj will say, “They need association.”
Pero como diría Avadhut Maharaj, "Ellos necesitan asociación."
Whenever someone … he goes, “Oh, they need association”,
Siempre que ve a alguien... dice, "Oh ellos necesitan asociación",
and he’s right.
y tiene razón.
Sthāne sthitāḥ śruti–gatāḿ tanu–vāń–manobhir (SB: 10.14.3),
Sthane sthitah? sruti–gatam´ tanu–van–manobhir (SB: 10.14.3),
when you get this association,
cuando obtienes ésta asociación,
bhaktyā sañjātayā bhaktyā (SB: 11.3.31),
bhaktya sañjataya bhaktya (SB: 11.3.31),
[it] ignites the candle, the flame,
ésta enciende la vela, la flama,
of Krishna conception in the heart.
de la concepción en el corazón de Krishna
These are metaphors: ‘flame’, ‘candle’, ‘seed’.
Estas son metáforas: 'flama', 'vela', 'semilla'.
It's always awakened, ignited, planted, grown, developed,
Siempre es despertada, encendida, plantada, crece, se desarrolla,
by association with a proper agent, a real agent.
a través de la asociación del agente apropiado, un verdadero agente.
That’s the concept.
ese es el concepto.